Guide to the Robert Moses Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, 1934-(1952-1970)
  - 1964: 1st volume
    - SPEECHES BY ROBERT MOSES--1964:
      - 35. NEW YORK CITY BASEBALL FEDERATION AWARD, HILTON HOTEL, 6/17 (Box 5)
      - 36. NEW YORK CITY BUILDING DEDICATION, FLUSHING MEADOW, 4/25 (Box 5)
      - 37. NEW YORK STATE CONFERENCE OF MAYORS, BELGIAN VILLAGE, FLUSHING MEADOW, 6/17 (Box 5)
      - 38. NEW YORK STATE LEGISLATORS LUNCHEON, FLUSHING MEADOW, 6/30 (Box 5)
      - 39. NEW YORK STATE PAVILION DEDICATION, FLUSHING MEADOW, 4/23 (Box 5)
      - 40. NEW YORK STATE PUBLISHERS ASSOCIATION, INC., LUNCHEON, CORONA, NEW YORK, 9/14 (Box 5)
      - 41. NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR OPENING, 4/22 (Box 5)
      - 42. PAVILION OF FINE ARTS OPENING, PRESS PREVIEW, FLUSHING MEADOW, 6/22 (Box 5)
      - 43. RCA PAVILION DEDICATION, FLUSHING MEADOW, 4/2 (Box 5)
      - 44. RHODE ISLAND, UNIVERSITY OF--HONORARY DEGREE OF DOCTOR OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION, 10/5 (Box 5)
      - 45. SHEA STADIUM, OPENING OF, FLUSHING MEADOW, 4/16 (Box 5)
      - 46. SILVER BUFFALO, BOY SCOUTS OF AMERICA, FLUSHING MEADOW, 7/14 (Box 5)
      - 47. SOCIETY OF THE FOUR ARTS, PALM BEACH, FLORIDA, 2/4 (Box 5)
      - 48. STATE THEATRE BUILDING DEDICATION, LINCOLN CENTER, 4/23 (Box 5)
      - 49. SUNKEN MEADOW STATE PARK--OPENING OF GOLF COURSES, 5/14 (Box 5)
      - 50. TERMINAL BUILDING AT LaGUARDIA AIRPORT--DEDICATION, 4/16 (Box 5)
      - 51. TEXAS PAVILIONS AND MUSIC HALL FLAG RAISING CEREMONY, FLUSHING MEADOW, 2/26 (Box 5)
      - 52. TRAVELERS INSURANCE COMPANIES LUNCHEON, TOP OF FAIR, 4/3 (Box 5)
      - 53. UNISPHERE, PRESENTATION BY U. S. STEEL TO WORLD'S FAIR, 4/18 (Box 5)
      - 54. UNITED STATES LEGISLATIVE LEADERS, TERRACE CLUB, 9/26 (Box 5)
      - 55. UTAH STATE DAY CEREMONIES, FLUSHING MEADOW, 7/24 (Box 5)
      - 56. VATICAN PAVILION, BLESSING AND DEDICATION, 4/19 (Box 5)
      - 57. VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE DEDICATION, 11/21 (Box 5)
      - 58. WAGNER, ROBERT, PROCLAMATION OF WORLD'S FAIR WEEK, CITY HALL, NEW YORK, 10/1 (Box 5)
      - 59. YALE UNIVERSITY FIFTY-FIFTH REUNION OF THE CLASS OF 1909, NEW HAVEN, CONNECTICUT, 6/20 (Box 5)
    - ARTICLES BY ROBERT MOSES--1964:
      - 1. AIRLANES--"A TALE OF TWO FAIRS FROM '39 TO '64", JUL.-AUG. (Box 5)
      - 2. AMUSEMENT BUSINESS "A MOSES-EYE VIEW: THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", 11/28 (Box 5)
      - 3. CHALLENGE AND OPPORTUNITY--PUBLIC WORKS--COLORADO MUNICIPALITIES, SEPT. (Box 5)
      - 4. CIRCUS AND THE FAIR, THE--CONTINENTAL CIRCUS, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 5. CONSTRUCTIONEER--"STATEMENT FOR CONSTRUCTIONEER MAGAZINE", 3/23 (Box 5)
      - 6. FAIR, THE CITY AND THE CRITICS, THE, 10/13 (Box 5)
      - 7. FASHIONING OF A FAIR, THE--OFFICIAL SOUVENIR BOOK, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 8. FESTIVAL OF JEWISH LITURGICAL MUSIC, 5/1 (Box 5)
      - 9. GATSBY & BEYOND--REPRINTED FROM LONG ISLAND PRESS, 6/14 (Box 5)
      - 10. GOOD SAMARITAN BALL--INTRODUCTION TO PROGRAM, 8/29 (Box 5)
      - 11. HOME IS THE SAILOR--BOOK REVIEW--N. Y. TIMES, 6/9 (Box 5)
      - 12. HOW TO DESTROY A CITY--HERALD TRIBUNE--AND REPLY BY ROBERT MOSES, 3/15 & 29 (Box 5)
      - 13. KOSTELANETZ' "WONDERLAND OF NEW YORK" ALBUM, ROBERT MOSES' NOTES REGARDING, APRIL (Box 5)
      - 14. LET'S GET THE PUBLIC INTO PUBLIC WORKS--KIWANIS MAGAZINE, SEPT. (Box 5)
      - 15. LITERARY GEMS, ROBERT MOSES--SHOW MAGAZINE, SEPT. (Box 5)
      - 16. MOSES, ROBERT, WARNS AGAINST 'MOB RULE--NATION'S BUSINESS, DEC. (Box 5)
      - 17. MUSIC JOURNAL--"MUSIC AT THE FAIR", APRIL (Box 5)
      - 18. MY VIEWS ON HIGHWAYS--THE HIGHWAY USER, SEPT. (Box 5)
      - 19. SATURDAY EVENING POST, REPRINT OF ARTICLE PUBLISHED IN--"SHOULD YOU BECOME A PUBLIC SERVANT?", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 20. SPECIAL COMMITTEE ON ETHICS--STATEMENT OF ROBERT MOSES AT ASSOCIATION OF THE BAR OF THE CITY OF NEW YORK, 2/7 (Box 5)
      - 21. SPELLMAN, FRANCIS CARDINAL--TWENTY FIVE YEARS ARCHBISHOP OF NEW YORK--"THE NEW YORKER", 5/23 (Box 5)
      - 22. SUPREME COURT ENTERS A JUNGLE, THE, DEC. (Box 5)
      - 23. SWEEP--GUEST EDITOR ROBERT MOSES, SPRING (Box 5)
      - 24. VAST WONDERLAND--"ROBERT MOSES TALKS ABOUT THE FAIR"--THE HIGHWAY USER, JUNE (Box 5)
      - 25. "WHY A FAIR? AND WHY THIS FAIR?" - N. Y. TIMES MAGAZINE, APR. 19 (Box 5)
    - ARTICLES ON ROBERT MOSES--1964:
      - 1. ADVANCE, THE--"ROBERT MOSES--NEW YORK'S MASTER BUILDER", 3/1 (Box 5)
      - 2. AMERICAN PUBLIC WORKS ASSOCIATION REPORTER--"ROBERT MOSES HEADS NATIONAL PUBLIC WORKS WEEK", FEB. (Box 5)
      - 3. ARCHITECTURAL FORUM--"MOSES BUILDS A FAIR", JAN. (Box 5)
      - 4. CONSULTING ENGINEER--"ROBERT MOSES", JULY (Box 5)
      - 5. ENGINEERING NEWS-RECORD--"ROBERT MOSES, THE MAN WHO BUILT THE WORLD'S FAIR", 4/23 (Box 5)
      - 6. HOLIDAY MAGAZINE--"THE INTRACTABLE ROBERT MOSES", JULY (Box 5)
      - 7. LIFELINE--"ROBERT MOSES", MAR.-APR. (Box 5)
      - 8. LOOK MAGAZINE--"BRASH BOSS OF A BILLION DOLLAR FAIR", 2/11 (Box 5)
      - 9. OGDENSBURG JOURNAL--"LUNCHEON WITH ROBERT MOSES", 1/27 (Box 5)
      - 10. OGDENSBURG JOURNAL--"WE WERE BOB MOSES' GUEST AT HIS GREATEST SHOW YET", 11/24 (Box 5)
      - 11. READER'S DIGEST--"MOSES (ROBERT) AND THE PROMISED LAND", SEPT. (Box 5)
  - 1964: 2nd volume
    - FAIR REPORTS--1964:
      - 1. BEAME, ABRAHAM--REPLY RE OPPOSITION TO POST-FAIR PARK PROGRAM, 5/22 (Box 5)
      - 2. DIRECTORS, JOINT ANNUAL MEETING OF MEMBERS AND--TOP OF FAIR, 1/22 (Box 5)
      - 3. FAIR FROM A TO Z, 4/16 (Box 5)
      - 4. FAIR IS FAIR--OFFICIAL WORLD'S FAIR SONG, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 5. FAIR NEWS BULLETIN, 2/22 (Box 5)
      - 6. FAIR NEWS BULLETIN, 3/22 (Box 5)
      - 7. FARMER, JAMES--ACTION FOR AN ORDER TO ALLOW PICKETING--AFFIDAVIT, 6/2 (Box 5)
      - 8. FARMER, JAMES VS. ROBERT MOSES--OPINION OF U. S. DISTRICT COURT, 6/30 (Box 5)
      - 9. FLUSHING MEADOW AND BEYOND--PROGRESS REPORT, 7/14 (Box 5)
      - 10. GUIDE BOOK TO FAIR, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 11. HALL OF SCIENCE POST-FAIR EXPANSION, 2/24 (Box 5)
      - 12. HALL OF SCIENCE DEDICATION, 9/9 (Box 5)
      - 13. HALL OF SCIENCE DEDICATION CEREMONY EXCERPTS, 9/9 (Box 5)
      - 14. INTERIM REPORT, 10/13 (Box 5)
      - 15. JORDAN MURAL CASE AFFIDAVIT TO NEW YORK STATE SUPREME COURT, 6/4 (Box 5)
      - 16. MAP, OFFICIAL SOUVENIR, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 17. NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR OPENING PROGRAM, 4/22 (Box 5)
      - 17a. OLYMPIC TRIALS IN CITY OF NEW YORK, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 18. OPERATION SAIL, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 19. PRESIDENT JOHNSON'S ADDRESS AT FAIR OPENING, 4/22 (Box 5)
      - 20. QUEENS ZOOLOGICAL AND BOTANICAL GARDENS POST-FAIR PLAN, 2/17 (Box 5)
      - 21. SCIENCE AT THE FAIR, JUNE (Box 5)
      - 22. TERRACE CLUB BOTTLE COLLECTION OF PEDRO CHICOTE, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 23. TICKETS, ADVANCE SALE OF--PRESS RELEASE, 3/2 (Box 5)
      - 24. VATIAN PAVILION BLESSING AND DEDICATION, 4/19 (Box 5)
  - 1964: 3rd volume
    - TBTA--1964:
      - 1. ANNUAL REPORT FOR 1964, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 2. PREFACE TO ANNUAL REPORT FOR 1964, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 3. ARTERIAL PROGRESS REPORT, 1/27 (Box 5)
      - 4. FORD TIMES--"WORLD'S LONGEST SUSPENSION BRIDGE", MARCH (Box 5)
      - 5. HARPER'S MAGAZINE--"THE GREATEST BRIDGE OF THEM ALL", NOV. (Box 5)
      - 6. HISTORICAL HIGHLIGHTS, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 7. LOWER MANHATTAN EXPRESSWAY, 7/1 (Box 5)
      - 8. LOWER MANATTAN EXPRESSWAY, NEED FOR, 7/15 (Box 5)
      - 9. LOWER MANHATTAN EXPRESSWAY, OPENING STATEMENT, PUBLIC HEARING, BOARD OF ESTIMATE, 12/22 (Box 5)
      - 10. MAP, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 11. NEW YORK TIMES--"NEW YORK, NEW YORK", 11/29 (Box 5)
      - 12. SPANNING THE NARROWS, 11/21 (Box 5)
      - 13. STATEN ISLAND ADVANCE - VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE OPENING, 11/20 (Box 5)
      - 14. SUNDAY NEWS--VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE OPENING, 11/15 (Box 5)
      - 15. VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE DEDICATION--PROGRAM, 11/21 (Box 5)
      - 16. WATERFRONT, THE EXPANDING NEW YORK, AUG. (Box 5)
    - MISCELLANEOUS--1964:
      - 1. AMERICAN CITY--APWA AT ATLANTIC CITY, OCT. (Box 5)
      - 2. NATIONAL SCULPTURE SOCIETY PROGRAM, 2/11 (Box 5)
      - 3. NEW YORK BUILDING SUPERINTENDENTS ASSOCIATION, 2/29 (Box 5)
      - 4. PUBLIC WORKS MEN OF THE YEAR, TOP TEN, 10/4 (Box 5)
      - 5. ROBERT MOSES STATE PARK DEDICATION--PROGRAM, 6/13 (Box 5)
      - 6. ROBERT MOSES STATE PARK--BROCHURE, 6/13 (Box 5)
      - 7. ROBERT MOSES STATE PARKWAY AND BEAVER ISLAND GOLF COURSE DEDICATION, 7/30 (Box 5)
      - 8. SHEA STADIUM DEDICATION, 4/17 (Box 5)
      - 9. SUNKEN MEADOW STATE PARK--NEW GOLF COURSES, 5/14 (Box 5)
  - 1964: 4th volume
    - FAIR ARTICLES--1964:
      - 1. AMERICAN BUILDER--FAIR ISSUE, MAY (Box 5)
      - 2. ARCHITECTURAL RECORD--"PREVIEW: NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965", FEB. (Box 5)
      - 3. BON APPETIT--"WORLD'S FAIR ON REVIEW", APRIL (Box 5)
      - 4. BUSINESS IN NEW YORK STATE--"SHOWCASE--THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", MAY-JUNE (Box 5)
      - 5. BUSINESS SCREEN--"FILM AT THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 6. CHASE MANHATTAN BANK--GUIDE TO NEW YORK CITY "OUR FAIR CITY", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 7. CONSTRUCTIONEER--"FAIR RUSHED TO COMPLETION", 3/23 (Box 5)
      - 8. CUE--"PREVIEW OF THE WORLD'S FAIR", 3/21 (Box 5)
      - 9. DIPLOMAT--"FAIR FOR ALL", MARCH (Box 5)
      - 10. DISCOVERY--"NEW YORK: THE WORLD'S BEST WORLD'S FAIR", SPRING (Box 5)
      - 11. DODGE NEWS--FAIR ISSUES, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 12. EQUINEWS--FAIR ISSUE, APRIL (Box 5)
      - 13. FEMME-LINES--"COME TO THE FAIR", JAN.- FEB. (Box 5)
      - 14. FLUSHING CHAMBER OF COMMERCE NEWSLETTER--"WORLD'S FAIR BUILDINGS COULD BE KEPT FOR PARK", JUNE (Box 5)
      - 15. FORD TIMES--"NEW YORK AND WORLD'S FAIR--SPECIAL ISSUE", MAY (Box 5)
      - 16. FOUNTAIN OF THE PLANETS, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 17. GENERAL FOODS "ARCHWAY TO UNDERSTANDING", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 18. GENERAL MOTORS--"LET'S GO TO THE FAIR AND FUTURAMA", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 19. GOOD HOUSEKEEPING--"THE WORLD'S FAIR HOUSE", MAY (Box 5)
      - 20. GREYHOUND MAP--"HOW TO SEE THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 21. HERALD TRIBUNE--ART BUCHWALD'S COLUMN: "A DAY AT THE FAIR", 5/24 (Box 5)
      - 22. HOLIDAY MAGAZINE--ARTICLES AND CARTOONS, JULY (Box 5)
      - 23. LADIES HOME JOURNAL--"COME TO THE FAIR", JULY (Box 5)
      - 24. LIFE MAGAZINE--"NEW YORK'S BILLION DOLLAR DREAM FAIR", 1/17 (Box 5)
      - 25. LIFE MAGAZINE--"NEW YORK'S SPECTACLE", 3/23 (Box 5)
      - 26. LIFE MAGAZINE--"A SMASHEROO OF A WORLD'S FAIR", 5/1 (Box 5)
      - 27. LONG ISLAND PRESS--"COME TO THE FAIR", 4/5 (Box 5)
      - 28. LONG ISLAND RAILROADER--WORLD'S FAIR ISSUE, 2/13 (Box 5)
      - 29. LOOK MAGAZINE--"NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR PREVIEW", 2/11 (Box 5)
      - 30. MASCULINES--"NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", FEB.- MAR. (Box 5)
      - 31. MISSOURI BUSINESS--"MISSOURI GOES TO THE FAIR", MARCH (Box 5)
      - 32. MORRELL MAGAZINE--"MORRELL AND THE ILLINOIS PAVILION", MAY-JUNE (Box 5)
      - 33. NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC SCHOOL BULLETIN, 2/3 (Box 5)
      - 34. NEW YORK, U. S. A.--"THE WORLD'S FAIR COMES TO NEW YORK" BY GEN. W. E. POTTER, FEB. (Box 5)
      - 35. NEWS--"THIS IS AN INVITATION", 2/16 (Box 5)
      - 36. NEWS--SPECIAL WORLD'S FAIR SECTION, 4/12 (Box 5)
      - 37. NEWSWEEK--"WHAT TO WEAR AT THE FAIR", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 38. NEWSWEEK--"WORLD'S FAIR PREVIEW", 1/13 (Box 5)
      - 39. NEWSWEEK--"FOR EVERYBODY FROM EVERYWHERE", 4/27 (Box 5)
      - 40. OIL MAGAZINE--"THE FLAIR OF THE FAIR", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 41. OLYMPIC TEAM TRIALS:, 1964
        - 41. A. BASKETBALL, APRIL (Box 5)
        - 41. B. BOXING, MAY (Box 5)
        - 41. C. JUDO, JUNE (Box 5)
        - 41. D. MEN'S TRACK AND FIELD, JULY (Box 5)
        - 41. E. ROWING, JULY (Box 5)
        - 41. F. FENCING, JULY (Box 5)
        - 41. G. GYMNASTICS, AUGUST (Box 5)
        - 41. H. SWIMMING--DIVING--WATER POLO, AUG.-SEPT. (Box 5)
        - 41. I. CYCLING, AUG.-SEPT. (Box 5)
        - 41. J. CANOEING, SEPT (Box 5)
      - 42. PAINTER AND DECORATOR--"FABULOUS NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR TO OPEN", MARCH (Box 5)
      - 43. PARADE MAGAZINE--"THE LAST OF THE BIG WORLD'S FAIRS", 2/2 (Box 5)
      - 44. PARIS MATCH--FAIR ARTICLES, MAY (Box 5)
      - 45. PLAYGROUND FOR DREAMERS--FAIR ARTICLES, 1964 (Box 5)
      - 46. PONTIAC SAFARI--PART I--FAIR ARTICLES, JAN.-FEB. (Box 5)
      - 46a. PONTIAC SAFARI--PART II--FAIR ARTICLES, MAR.-APR. (Box 5)
      - 47. POPULAR MECHANICS--"INSIDE 1964's BIGGEST SHOW ON EARTH", FEB. (Box 5)
      - 48. READER'S DIGEST REPRINT--"COMING: THE MOST MARVELOUS FAIR EVER!", JAN. (Box 5)
      - 49. SATURDAY EVENING POST--"RELIGION AT THE WORLD'S FAIR", 3/28 (Box 5)
      - 50. SENIOR SCHOLASTIC--SPECIAL FAIR ISSUE, 4/3 (Box 5)
      - 51. SEVENTEEN-AT-SCHOOL--"A HOMEMAKING TEACHER'S CLASSROOM GUIDE TO THE WORLD'S FAIR", FEB. (Box 5)
      - 52. SEVENTEEN--"FABULOUS PREVIEW--WORLD'S FAIR 1964", FEB. (Box 5)
      - 53. SHELL NEWS--"THE WORLD'S BIGGEST FAIR", JAN.-FEB. (Box 5)
      - 54. TIME--"FAIRS" AND "THE NEWEST FAIR", 1/17 (Box 5)
      - 55. TIME--"A CONFIDENTIAL GUIDE TO THE NEW YORK FAIR", 6/5 (Box 5)
      - 56. TIMES, NEW YORK--"BEGIN THE FAIR AT TIMES SQUARE", 4/5 (Box 5)
      - 57. TV GUIDE--"OPENING NIGHT AT THE WORLD'S FAIR", 4/19 (Box 5)
      - 58. UNICEF--"IT'S A SMALL WORLD", 1964 (Box 5)
      - 59. UNICEF--NEWS OF THE WORLD'S CHILDREN, APR. (Box 5)
      - 60. VOGUE--"ABC OF THE WORLD'S FAIR WONDERS", 1/15 (Box 5)
      - 61. WESTSIDER--WORLD'S FAIR ISSUE, SPRING (Box 5)
  - 1965: 1st volume
    - FAIR
      - 1. ADMISSION PRICE INCREASE--RELEASE, 1/12 (Box 5)
      - 2. ART '65, 6/28 (Box 5)
      - 3. BELL SYSTEM--"FUN AT THE FAIR", 1965 (Box 5)
      - 4. CHURCHILL EXHIBITION--RELEASE, 2/7 (Box 5)
      - 5. CONTINENTAL MAGAZINE--"THIS IS THE YEAR FOR THE FAIR", 1965 (Box 5)
      - 6. CUE MAGAZINE--"THE WORLD'S FAIR", 4/17 (Box 5)
      - 7. EDUCATIONAL TOURS PROGRAM, 9/13 (Box 5)
      - 8. THE FAIR IN 1965-- PROGRESS REPORT (Box 5)
      - 9. FAMILY FUN AT THE FAIR, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 10. FOOD AT THE FAIR, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 11. FORD TIMES, 5/1965 (Box 5)
      - 12. FREE AT THE FAIR, WHAT'S, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 13. GOOD HOUSEKEEPING --"ANOTHER LOOK AT THE WORLD'S FAIR", APRIL (Box 5)
      - 14. GUIDE BOOK, OFFICIAL, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 15. HIGHLIGHTS OF THE FAIR, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 16. HOW TO COME TO THE FAIR, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 17. JETAGE AIRLANES--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR, 7/8 (Box 5)
      - 18. JOURNAL AMERICAN--"THE FAIR '65: WHAT'S NEW, WHAT'S GOOD", 4/18 (Box 5)
      - 19. LONG ISLAND PRESS--"WORLD'S FAIR LEGACY", 7/18 (Box 5)
      - 20. LOOK MAGAZINE --"NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1965", 4/20 (Box 5)
      - 21. MAP, OFFICIAL SOUVENIR, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 22. NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC --"THE FAIR REOPENS", APRIL (Box 5)
      - 23. NATIONAL REVIEW--"FAREWELL TO THE FAIR", 11/2 (Box 5)
      - 24. NEW YORK STATE VACATION LANDS--WORLD'S FAIR EDITION, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 25. PARENTS' MAGAZINE--"WORLD'S FARE", MARCH (Box 5)
      - 26. POPULAR PHOTOGRAPHY--"WORLD'S FAIR PICTURE TAKING AND EXPOSURE GUIDE", APRIL (Box 5)
      - 27. POST-FAIR ENGINEERING REPORT, 7/23 (Box 5)
      - 28. READER'S DIGEST REPRINT--"TO GET THE MOST OUT OF THE WORLD'S FAIR", 1965 (Box 5)
      - 29. SOUVENIR BOOK, OFFICIAL, 1965 (Box 5)
      - 30. TIME MAGAZINE--"FAIRS--SECOND TIME AROUND", 4/30 (Box 5)
      - 31. WESTSIDER MAGAZINE--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1965, SPRING (Box 5)
  - 1965: 2nd volume
    - ARTICLES BY ROBERT MOSES--1965:
      - Newsday Columns
        - 1. FROM THE BRIDGE, 10/30 (Box 6)
        - 2. NEW YORK, NEW YORK, 11/6 (Box 6)
        - 3. POPE PAUL, 11/13 (Box 6)
        - 4. THE OPEN ROAD, 11/20 (Box 6)
        - 5. THE FOUR METROPOLITAN HORSEMEN, 11/27 (Box 6)
        - 6. NONE BUT THE BRAVE, 12/4 (Box 6)
        - 7. REAPPORTIONMENT: PART I, 12/11 (Box 6)
        - 8. REAPPORTIONMENT: PART II, 12/18 (Box 6)
        - 9. THE FIFTH ESTATE, 12/24 (Box 6)
        - 10. STATUS, 12/31 (Box 6)
      - Other
        - 11. BRIDGE, THE GREAT--FOREWORD BY ROBERT MOSES, 1965 (Box 6)
        - 12. DIRECTORS' REPORT, WORLD'S FAIR--FOREWORD, 7/8 (Box 6)
        - 13. FLATBUSH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE "A VERY SPECIAL DEDICATION", MARCH (Box 6)
        - 14. WORLD'S FAIR PRESS RELEASE, 3/12 (Box 6)
        - 15. SWOPE, THE WORLD OF--BOOK REVIEW--EDITOR & PUBLISHER, 10/16 (Box 6)
    - REMARKS BY ROBERT MOSES--1965:
      - 1. BATTERY PARKING GARAGE ADDITION--GROUNDBREAKING, 12/17 (Box 6)
      - 2. BERLIN DAY CEREMONIES, BERLIN PAVILION, 5/21 (Box 6)
      - 3. CHURCHILL PAVILION, DEDICATION OF, 4/28 (Box 6)
      - 4. CONSOLIDATED EDISON EMPLOYEES, SINGER BOWL, 7/17 (Box 6)
      - 5. DELACORTE, GEORGE, ANIMATED CLOCK DEDICATION, CENTRAL PARK ZOO, 6/24 (Box 6)
      - 6. DELACORTE FOUNTAIN DEDICATION, COLUMBUS CIRCLE, 10/11 (Box 6)
      - 7. ENGINEERS, AWARD OF THE KINGS COUNTY CHAPTER OF SOCIETY OF PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS, 5/8 (Box 6)
      - 8. FAIR AND THE MASONS--ANNUAL COMMUNICATION OF THE GRAND LODGE, FREE AND ACCEPTED MASONS, 5/4 (Box 6)
      - 9. FLORIDA GRAND OPENING CEREMONIES, 5/8 (Box 6)
      - 10. FLORIDA CITRUS WATER SKI SHOW, DEDICATION, 3/2 (Box 6)
      - 11. FORT HAMILTON PARKWAY PLAYGROUND--TRANSFER FROM TRIBOROUGH TO PARK DEPARTMENT, 6/23 (Box 6)
      - 12. GEMINI 4 SPACECRAFT EXHIBIT--FAIR, 7/8 (Box 6)
      - 13. GENERAL CIGAR PAVILION, DEDICATION OF ROBERT BURNS MEMORABILIA EXHIBIT AT FAIR, 8/18 (Box 6)
      - 14. GOLDEN, JOHN--DEDICATION OF PARK, BAYSIDE, 10/18 (Box 6)
      - 15. GOOD SAMARITAN BALL--THIRD ANNUAL, 8/28 (Box 6)
      - 16. HANSE, GILBERT--TESTIMONIAL DINNER, 9/18 (Box 6)
      - 17. HARVARD UNIVERSITY DAY, NEW ENGLAND PAVILION, 5/13 (Box 6)
      - 18. HIGHWAY OFFICIALS (STATE) DINNER, 51st ANNUAL CONVENTION OF THE AMERICAN ASSOCIATION--TOP OF FAIR, 10/7 (Box 6)
      - 19. INTERNATIONAL PUBLISHERS DAY AT FAIR--"THE CITY, THE FAIR, THE WORLD AND THE BOOK", 6/10 (Box 6)
      - 20. KAZAN, ABRAHAM E.--TESTIMONIAL DINNER, 10/24 (Box 6)
      - 21. KIWANIS INTERNATIONAL, MADISON SQUARE GARDEN, 7/6 (Box 6)
      - 22. LEGION OF VALOR--TESTIMONIAL ON LEGION OF VALOR DAY, U. S. PAVILION, 6/24 (Box 6)
      - 23. LIONS CLUB OF NEW YORK--OUTSTANDING ACHIEVEMENT AWARD, 5/4 (Box 6)
      - 24. MARCH OF DIMES INTERNATIONAL BALL, TOP OF FAIR, 4/21 (Box 6)
      - 25. MASONS--KNIGHTS OF COLUMBUS DAY AT FAIR, 7/24 (Box 6)
      - 26. MASSACHUSETTS DAY, NEW ENGLAND STATES EXHIBIT, 9/12 (Box 6)
      - 27. MENDEL, FATHER GREGOR--GARDEN OF HEREDITY, DEDICATION AT VATICAN PAVILION, 6/20 (Box 6)
      - 28. MEXICAN PAVILION--INAUGURATION OF ART EXHIBIT AND REOPENING, 5/25 (Box 6)
      - 29. MISSOURI DAY, MISSOURI PAVILION, 8/27 (Box 6)
      - 30. NATIONAL EDUCATION ASSOCIATION DAY, TOP OF FAIR, 6/26 (Box 6)
      - 31. NEW JERSEY STATE DAY CEREMONIES, NEW JERSEY PAVILION, 6/24 (Box 6)
      - 32. NEW YORK STATE CONFERENCE OF TRIAL JUDGES, JUDICIAL CONFERENCE OF STATE OF NEW YORK, CROTONVILLE, N. Y., 6/18 (Box 6)
      - 33. NEW YORK STATE COUNTY JUDGES ASSOCIATION, NEW YORK STATE PAVILION, 5/21 (Box 6)
      - 34. NEW YORK STATE DAY CEREMONIES, NEW YORK STATE PAVILION, 4/22 (Box 6)
      - 35. NEW YORK STATE LEGISLATORS DAY, TOP OF FAIR, 7/14 (Box 6)
      - 36. O'CASEY, SEAN--IRISH NIGHT AT OVERSEAS PRESS CLUB, 3/16 (Box 6)
      - 37. ORDER OF MERIT--RECEIVES RANK OF COMMANDER IN ORDER OF MERIT, REPUBLIC OF ITALY--ON BOARD RAFFAELLO, 8/3 (Box 6)
      - 38. PENNSYLVANIA EXHIBIT DEDICATION--COURT OF UNIVERSE, 6/13 (Box 6)
      - 39. PHILADELPHIA 1976 BI-CENTENNIAL COMMITTEE LUNCHEON, TOP OF FAIR, 9/15 (Box 6)
      - 40. PIPE NIGHT AT PLAYERS--COMMENTATORS, 11/28 (Box 6)
      - 41. QUEENS DAY AT FAIR, NEW YORK STATE PAVILION, 5/17 (Box 6)
      - 42. ST. GEORGE ASSOCIATION OF NEW YORK CITY POLICE DEPARTMENT COMMUNION BREAKFAST, WALDORF--GOLDEN RULE AWARD, 5/2 (Box 6)
      - 43. SALES EXECUTIVES CLUB OF NEW YORK, TOP OF FAIR, 7/29 (Box 6)
      - 44. SALVATION ARMY--BABYLON TOWN CENTENNIAL SERVICE UNIT DINNER, BABYLON, 5/26 (Box 6)
      - 45. SCIENCE, HALL OF--FIRST MEETING OF TRUSTEES, 1/25 (Box 6)
      - 46. SOUND CROSSING--DINNER OF WESTCHESTER COUNTY ASSOCIATION, EASTCHESTER, 11/30 (Box 6)
      - 47. SPANISH PAVILION CLOSING, 10/17 (Box 6)
      - 48. STEVENSON, ADLAI E.--MEMORIAL CEREMONIES, ILLINOIS PAVILION, 8/26 (Box 6)
      - 49. TOASTMASTERS INTERNATIONAL GOLDEN GAVEL CEREMONY, BELL SYSTEM PAVILION, 8/21 (Box 6)
      - 50. TOBIN, AUSTIN--INTRODUCTION AT BUILDING CONGRESS LUNCHEON, ASTOR HOTEL, 9/29 (Box 6)
      - 51. TOKYO OLYMPIAD FILM AT NEW YORK CITY BUILDING, 9/19 (Box 6)
      - 52. TRANSIT AUTHORITY--PRESENTATION OF PLAQUE ON FIFTIETH ANNIVERSARY OF SUBWAY SERVICE TO BROOKLYN AND QUEENS, LOWENBRAU GARDENS, FAIR, 7/22 (Box 6)
      - 53. WESTINGHOUSE TIME CAPSULE II--DEPOSITING AT WESTINGHOUSE PAVILION, 10/16 (Box 6)
      - 54. WOMEN'S HALL OF FAME DEDICATION, WOMEN'S HOSPITALITY CENTER, FAIR, 5/27 (Box 6)
      - 55. WORLD'S FAIR CLOSING, 10/17 (Box 6)
      - 56. WORLD'S FAIR DIRECTORS AND MEMBERS SPECIAL MEETING, 11/16 (Box 6)
      - 57. WORLD'S FAIR EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE SPECIAL MEETING, 1/26 (Box 6)
      - 58. WORLD'S FAIR FASHION SHOW, NEW ENGLAND PAVILION, 6/1 (Box 6)
      - 59. WORLD'S FAIR PROMOTION COMMITTEE--MESSAGE TO QUEENS, HOTEL WHITMAN, 4/19 (Box 6)
      - 60. NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR REOPENING DAY CEREMONIES, 4/21 (Box 6)
      - 61. WORLD'S FAIR, REPORT TO EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE, 12/14 (Box 6)
      - 62. WORLD'S FAIR SCIENCE CONTEST AWARDS BREAKFAST, TOP OF FAIR, 8/22 (Box 6)
  - 1965: 3rd volume
    - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY REPORTS--1965:
      - 1. ARTERIAL PROGRESS, 2/23 (Box 6)
      - 2. ARTERIAL PROGRESS, 11/8 (Box 6)
      - 3. ANNUAL REPORT, 3/31/66 (Box 6)
      - 4. BATTERY PARKING GARAGE--LOWER MANHATTAN--ADDITION, 10/6 (Box 6)
      - 5. FACILITIES OF TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE & TUNNEL AUTHORITY, NOV. (Box 6)
      - 6. GRAND CENTRAL-NORTHERN STATE PARKWAY WIDENING, AND SUGGESTED FUTURE CLEARVIEW EXPRESSWAY SOUTHERLY EXTENSION, 11/29 (Box 6)
      - 7. LOWER MANHATTAN ELEVATED EXPRESSWAY, 11/15 (Box 6)
      - 8. MAP, TBTA, 1965 (Box 6)
      - 9. MILLER HIGHWAY AND HENRY HUDSON PARKWAY--PLAN TO INCREASE CAPACITY, 11/22 (Box 6)
      - 10. MILL ROCK, WARD'S ISLAND, RANDALL'S ISLAND, TRIBOROUGH HEADQUARTERS, CITY BUILDING--FLUSHING MEADOW PARK, 10/18 (Box 6)
      - 11. NEW YORK AT THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR--THE CITY, ITS CULTURE, 1965 (Box 6)
      - 12. PELHAM BAY SHORE DRIVE, 3/4 (Box 6)
      - 13. QUEENSBORO BRIDGE--MANHATTAN TERMINAL, 2/8 (Box 6)
      - 14. QUEENS MIDTOWN TUNNEL--THIRD TUBE, 12/29 (Box 6)
      - 15. SOUND BRIDGE, 2/15 (Box 6)
      - 16. SOUND CROSSING--TRAFFIC, EARNINGS AND FEASIBILITY OF, 7/1 (Box 6)
      - 17. STATEN ISLAND IMPROVEMENTS AND NEXT STEPS, 8/16 (Box 6)
      - 18. TRIBOROUGH BONDHOLDERS--STATEMENT TO, 11/15 (Box 6)
      - 19. VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE--TWELFTH ANNUAL HONOR AWARD TO BUILDERS OF BRIDGE BY KINGS COUNTY CHAPTER, N. Y. STATE SOCIETY OF PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS, 5/8 (Box 6)
    - MISCELLANEOUS--1965:
      - 1. EL ALCAZAR, MADRID, SPAIN--NEWSPAPER ARTICLE, 2/19/65 (Box 6)
      - 2. LONG ISLAND CATHOLIC--"VOTE OF CONFIDENCE FOR ROBERT MOSES", 5/27/65 (Box 6)
      - 3. LONG ISLAND PRESS EDITORIAL--"BOB MOSES, SPIRITED AT 76", 2/24/65 (Box 6)
      - 3. ANNUAL REPORT, POWER AUTH. OF THE STATE OF N. Y., 3/1/65 (Box 6)
  - 1966: 1st volume
    - ARTICLES 1966
      - 1. Falls Follies - Foreword, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 2. General Contractors Association Bulletin, February (Box 6A)
      - 3. Good Samaritan Ball Program Introduction, August 27, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 4. Newsweek - "FDR in Perspective" - Book Review of "The First New Deal", December 12, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 5. New York Life Insurance Co. "Should You Be a Public Servant?", 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 6. None But the Brave - Flatbush, March 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 7. Safety and Our Highways, September, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 8. Westsider - "The Changing Face of Manhattan", Spring 1966 (Box 6A)
    - SPEECHES 1966